Welcome to our final topic in lesson five.
Your team just finished a massive project
and everyone is exhausted.
What's your next move?
In sports, the post-game recovery protocol
is as important as the pre-game warmup.
In business, it should be no different.
Facilitating team recovery is the intentional process
of helping your team recharge and reset
after a period of intense effort.
It prevents burnout, reinforces the value of their work,
and prepares them for the next challenge.
After a grueling quarter end,
a manager didn't immediately launch
into planning for the next quarter.
She dedicated the first team meeting of the new quarter
entirely to retrospective and recovery.
They celebrated the wins, discussed the lessons learned,
and she gave everyone an extra half a day to recharge.
The team came back energized and focused.
At Velvet Suite, we practice the 90-Day Way.
And at the end of every quarter, we give a reset day,
which is a half day to focus on a few things.
Collective reflection, recharge,
and putting together our thoughts
around what will make the next 90-Day Way even stronger.
Your play is to plan a recovery protocol.
Look ahead at your team's calendar.
After the next big deadline or project launch,
what is the one small thing you can do
to facilitate team recovery?
I want you to schedule it now.
Your team is facing a mandatory crunch time
to meet a critical deadline.
You can't change the workload,
you can lead their recovery.
How do you proactively plan for a post-deadline recovery
to prevent burnout and acknowledge their effort?
Turn to the team's recovery protocols drill
in your playbook.
It provides a template for planning
a post-crunch recovery strategy
that rebuilds energy and reinforces trust.
This concludes lesson five.
You are now equipped with strategies
to manage your own energy and to lead your team
in a way that ensures sustainability,
long-term performance, and health and vitality.
And our final lesson will focus on the victory lap,
integrating your learnings and plannings
for your next season of leadership.
I'll see you there.
You